

Navneet Singh

Java Backend Developer

My Contact

singhnavneet.1711@gmail.com

(+91 7619123723

Delhi, India

Portfolio

(in) linkedin.com/navneet-singh

github.com/SinghNavneet17

Technical Skill

HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | Java | Hibernate | Spring Boot | Maven | MySQL

Soft Skill

Team collaboration | Proactive Problem Solving | Leadership

Education Background

Web Development Masai School

4/2022 - 2/2023

B.E,Mechanical Engineering RNSIT Bengaluru, Karnataka

8/2016 - 8/2020

Work Experience

CoEdify Technologies

8/2023 - 1/2024

worked as Software Developer at Coedify, utilized diverse technologies develop custom software for internal projects. Additionally, contributed to debugging and feature development for third-party clients.

Bosch Rexroth(Internship)

7/2019 - 8/2019

Worked on Controlling the movement of pistons using electro-pneumatic PLC which resulted in the automation of various Processes.

About Me

A full-stack web developer with a specialization in Java Backend development. Judicious and creative when crafting effective websites, apps, and platforms.

Personal Projects

Payment Wallet Application



A REST API that performs all the CRUD operations for the online Payment Application with user validation at every step

 This project was collaboratively built by a team of 5 developers, executed in 5 days

Features:

- Sign up, log In, log out modules, authentication with session uuid.
- Customers can add a bank account to their wallets.
- Add cash into your wallet, check balance, and bill payment.
- Add beneficiary, Transfer money into another wallet

TechStack:

Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySql

Areas of Responsibility:

- · Created API for Login, Signup, and Logout.
- Create API for Bill payment.

Shine Website





Shine is a job search and career management platform.

 The website has an end-to-end flow and various functionalities to enhance the user experience.

Features:

- Build login, register, courses, and payments page.
- We implemented the add-to-cart feature.
- Implemented filter, applied coupon & other functionalities.

TechStack:

• HTML, CSS, JavaSctipt

Areas of Responsibility:

- Created Login, signup, courses & payments page.
- implemented all functionalities.

Certificates

- JAVA (Hacker Rank) (1)
- SQL (Hacker Rank) (H)